Almkdad Ali

Software Engineer

Detailed-oriented software engineer with 4+ years of experience in full-stack development and system design. Worked in startups and enterprises as well as a freelancer, in which I use up-to-date engineering solutions to provide highly efficient and reliable software.



almkdad.m.ali@gmail.com

+420 702 008 753

Prague, Czech

linkedin.com/in/almkdad-ali

github.com/GuruOfMind

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Test Engineer | Azure DevOps Certicon

04/2022 - Present

Prague - Czech

Czech technology company involved in the innovation and development of SW and HW solutions for the areas of healthcare, and automotive industries

- Develop test cases and prioritize testing activities.
- Designing and executing manual and automated tests according to requirements.
- Finalizing and documenting testing procedures.

Technology Stack: EXAM, HiL, Inca, Jira, Conan, CMake, Azure DevOps, Pvthon

Python Developer Segron

01/2022 - 04/2022

Remote

SEGRON is a leader in the next generation of active testing, offering automated solutions to test digital services

Responsibilites

- Implementing dashboard for monitoring the revenue assurance for clients using Grafana.
- · Participating in tariffs engines implementations according to specifications and requirements
- Implementing web-based UI for admins and for clients using Angular.

Technology Stack: Angular, Django, Python, Jira, PostgreSQL

Software Engineer Burgas Tech

01/2020 - 12/2021 Svria

Responsibilities

- Architect, designing, developing and deploying new features for
- Work in close collaboration with UX/UI team to improve user experience.
- Participated heavily in requirements validation and release planning as well as issue tracking.
- Create and develop APIs using Django, and Nodejs that serves 10+ thousands of users.

Technology Stack: Flutter, Firebase, Django, Docker.

Software Engineer iSoft

03/2017 - 01/2020 Svria

Technology Stack: PHP, Javascript, MySQL, Java.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. of Engineering (ICTE)

Tartous University

2018 Tartous, Syria

Courses

 Information Technology **Engineering Stream**

TECHNICAL SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Autonomous Car Traffic Signs detection and alarming System

Smart India Hackathon National Qualifications, Build CNN-based model to recognize and detect Traffic signs using Python and Google Colab.

Sequence-to-sequence task-oriented dialogue system

Build production-ready dialogue system model using Python, Tensorflow, Deep

Build Dashboard to analyze Twitter data

- Build and develop data pipeline for user sentiment analysis on the Middle East stock market.
- Scrapes Twitter tweets to predict how people may feel about particular stocks in real-time.
- Use Apache Kafka, Apache Spark, Scrapy and Flask for the API.

ACTIVITIES

Smart India Hackathon (2020)

Google Android Certificate Bootcamp - India (08/2019 - 10/2020)

SCPC (2016)

Tartous CPC (2017)

Tishreen CPC (2014 - 2015)

Syrian Scientific Olympiad (2008)

Informatics

LANGUAGES

Arabic Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency



Talent without Borders.
Imagine Foundation e.V.
joinimagine.org

02/17/2021

Recommendation letter for Almkdad Ali

Dear colleague -

I hope this finds you well.

I'm writing to you to strongly endorse Almkdad Ali for a technical role in your company.

We are a social venture that supports young aspiring talents from non European countries in finding a challenging new job in Germany. We run a selective 4 week digital boot camp for full stack developers, data scientists/engineers and software automation testers. Over the course of the program, we identify candidates whose talent, passion and work ethic significantly stand out from their peers.

Almkdad Ali is an outstanding Data scientist who ranks in the top 10% of our peer group.

English communication Strong – validated in multiple rounds of 1:1 interviews

Technical skills High & up to date – on par with candidates in Germany

Unique qualities Extensive work experience with European/US/intl. teams

EU 'Blue Card' eligibility Yes – Almkdad is prepared to arrange their own work visa

Maturity Mid-Level – 3 years of work experience

Please feel free to reach out to me personally at johann@joinimagine.org in case of any question.

Warm regards & herzliche Grüße -

Dr. Johann Daniel Harnoss

Joann Hory &

Founder & CEO